8：30了，8：00的校车10分钟后就要到了
It's 8:30, guys. The 8:00 bus will be here in 10 minutes.
我还没准备好
And I still gotta get ready.
Ben. School.
忘了给你们，家长联谊会邀请
本，上学了
Forgot to give you guys this. It's a letter from the Parents Association.
凯罗，这没什么意思的
Ixnay on the etterlay, Carol.
-给我 -我来看看
- I'll take it. - Let me see that.
“贵家长，学校的每周舞会无法进行下去”
"Dear fellow parents, our program of weekly dances is in jeopardy...
“因为有些家长没有履行他们的义务”
"owing to the fact that many of you have not fulfilled...
“没有陪同子女参加舞会”
"your parental responsibilities and made yourselves available for chaperoning.
“谁不来谁心中有数，更重要的是 我们心中有数”
"You know who you are and, more importantly, we know who you are.
“敬礼，家长联谊会主席..”
"Sincerely, Mrs. Adolf Hitler."
“琼.亨克利，阿道夫老师” 很友善的一对信
"June Hinckley, President of the Parents Association." Nice tone.
爸妈都那么忙.
Now, come on now, busy people like you guys have far better things to do...
哪有空去体育馆那种脏地方
than to hang around a smelly gym.
-让麦克丢脸 -对
- Embarrassing Mike. - Yeah.
不，不
I mean, no.
丢脸？
Embarrass?
妈妈，这是她说的
That was her word, not my word, Mom.
我不介意爸妈出席舞会
I don't care if they chaperone dances. Bye.
因为你从来没参加过舞会
That's 'cause you've never been to one.
麦克，这种信以前也有过？
Mike, did you get one of these letters?
来过
Yeah, sure.
在哪？
Well? Where is it?
妈妈拜托你相信我
Come on, Mom. Give me some kind of credit here.
我是不想用这破玩意儿麻烦你们
Look, I'm not gonna bother you guys with a stupid letter like that.
我帮你们筛选过了
Look, I try to screen these things for you guys.
丢弃垃圾邮件
You know, you know, cut down on the junk mail...
节约你们宝贵的时间
protect your valuable time.
都丢到厕所里面去了
It's stuck to the ceiling in the boys' john.
(English Subtitle) Growing.Pains.S01E16 -= The.Seavers.VS.The.Cleavers =- Subripped by zerox
-本，上车 -不去就赶不上了
- Ben, the bus. - Use it or lose it.
本，你花太多的时间学习.
Come on, Ben, I think you're spending far too much time studying...
都没时间去玩了
and not nearly enough horsing around.
Hey!
本知道老爸在说笑，对吧？
I'm kidding. Ben knows when the old dad is kidding. Right, Ben?
是，老爷
Aye, milord.
“是，老爷”？
"Aye, milord"?
这是里的台词 学校今年的舞台剧
It's from Robin Hood. That's the school play this year.
所以叫我“老爷”不是出于尊重
You mean you weren't calling me "milord" as a measure of respect?
这才有意思嘛
That's funny, Dad.
爸爸是跟你开玩笑
See, he does know when his old dad's kidding.
今年我要参演
This year I'm going to get a part.
记得去年你没被选上，心都碎了
Well, let's hope, but I remember last year's auditions, how heartbroken you were.
行了爸爸，去年我还小呢
Come on, Dad. I was just a kid.
这么说你成了3年级唯一的大人.
Oh, I see. So this year as the only adult in the third grade...
你有优势
you ought to have a big edge.
就是这样
That's how I figure it.
祝你好运
Now good luck.
再见了
Bye, honey.
马到成功!
Break a leg!
什么？
What?
这是成语
Figure of speech.
杰森.
Jason...
你在麦克这个年纪.
when you were Mike's age would you have been afraid...
父母陪同参加舞会，你感到丢脸吗？
or embarrassed to have your parents chaperone?
对，我也经历过
Oh, sure. I went through that stage.
我父亲自告奋勇陪我参加学校活动
My dad volunteered to chaperone one of our class trips.
我就求他别去了
I begged him not to.
我说，“爸爸，我不会干些出格的事”
I said, "Dad, but I'm not going to do anything."
他说“那就好，有我在”
He said, "Well, that's fine. Then you can not do it with me there."
爸，气色挺好的 妈，你也是
Hey, looking good, Dad. Vicious ensemble, Mom.
-住你们今天愉快 -且慢!
- You both have a nice day, now, you hear? - Halt!
妈，我要错过校车了
Mom, I might miss that darn bus.
打开拉链
Open the coat.
酷吧？
Is this cool or what?
麦克，穿成这样能上学吗？
Mike, do you really think you've dressed appropriately for school?
不，怎么能这样？
Heck, no. Why would I want to do that?
-换衣服 -爸？
- Change now. - Dad?
麦克，若你真的认为.
Mike. Now, Mike, if you think that this conveys...
这能代表你和家人的形象
the proper image, not just for yourself, but for the family you represent...
那么你完全可以挂一个鸡头出去
then, by all means, go ahead and wear a rubber fowl on your stomach.
再见
See you.
杰森
Jason.
不知道为什么，热死了
I don't know why that works, but it's really starting to burn me up.
开学才一天 你不能因此断定学校不好
You know, you shouldn't judge the school by the first day.
而且你要体谅那些普通人
And you have to overlook all the average people.
这只是所公立学校
It is a public school.
这个我习来惯了
Well, I'm used to that, Carol.
洛杉矶也有许多普通人
You'd be surprised how many average people there are in Los Angeles.
我的自然老师甚至不许我做.
My old science teacher wouldn't even let me build a small model...
高热原子核的实验
of a thermonuclear device for a science project.
-裂变还是聚变？ -当然是聚变
- Fission or fusion? - Oh, fusion, of course.
“当然是”
Of course.
我打算要适应这里
I plan to fit in at this school.
我还加入了舞会组织委员会
I've already joined the dance decoration committee.
Oh?
那么你会参加明晚的舞会？
Will you be at the dance then tomorrow night?
对
Sure.
那你会跳舞？
Will you be dancing?
还没决定，也许当观察员
I haven't made up my mind yet. I might just observe.
嗨，麦克
Hi, Mike.
嗨，臭嘴巴
Hey, skunk-breath.
我哥哥
Brother.
麦克，是你吗？
Mike, is that you?
什么事？
What'd I do?
没什么
Nothing.
怎么样？
What do you think?
-很像你 -对
- It's you, Dad. - Yeah.
我的病人也这么说
That's what all the patients said.
爸爸!听我说.
Dad, Dad! Wait till you...
这里
Up here, Ben.
爸爸，我被选上了
Dad, I got a part! I got cast!
太好了!
Hey, all right! Good for you!
演什么角色？罗宾汉的部将？
What'd you get? One of Robin's merry men?
不
Nope.
-修道士？ -不，更好的
- Friar Tuck? - Nope. Better.
-罗宾汉？ -不，更好的
- Not Robin? - No, better.
-什么？ -演一块石头
- What? - A rock.
一块石头？
A rock?
一块英国石头
An English rock.
希望演舞台据.
Well, I hope the hours required rehearsing this part...
不会影响你的功课
won't interfere with your studies.
好就好在这
That's the best part.
我可以上台，参加派对.
I can be in the play...
而我只需要躺着不动就行了
go to all the parties and all I have to do is lay there.
我的石头儿子
My son, the rock.
对!
Yeah!
杰森，下面说说这件汗衫
Now, Jason, I want to talk to you about this shirt.
这形象不仅代表你
Now, if this is the proper image you wish to convey...
还代表你的家人
not only for yourself, but for the family you represent.
好吧
Okay, all right.
真可惜
All right, it's a shame, though.
我还以为能穿这个陪你参加舞会
I was thinking of wearing this when your mom and I chaperone your school dance.
什么？
What?
你们真的要去舞会？
You're not really going to chaperone?
骗你们的
Had you going there for a second, didn't I?
-太好啊 -是啊
- Put it there. - Yeah.
等等，怎么了？
Hey, wait a minute. What's this?
-什么事？ -什么事？
- What? - What?
你们俩平生第一次一个鼻孔出气了
For the first time in your lives, you two agree on something.
这才像样
That's better.
我还以为你不在乎家长陪同出席呢
I thought you said you didn't care whether they chaperoned or not.
不在乎，真的
I don't. Really.
凯罗，你从来不去舞会
Carol, you don't even go to these dances.
说不定这次会，我还没决定
Well, I might go to this one. I'm keeping my options open.
她想去是因为门口那书呆子也去
She just wants to go because that geek out on the front porch wants to go.
他不是书呆子，他刚从洛杉矶转学过来
He's not a geek. He's from Los Angeles.
凯罗，你在他面前都喘气了
You're breathing heavy for him, Carol.
才不是，我们在讨论核武器
I am not. We were discussing nuclear weapons.
听见了吧？没什么的
See? Perfectly harmless.
你害怕爸妈陪同出席
Carol, you're just afraid that if Mom and Dad chaperone...
你就不能化妆，不能跳贴身舞.
you won't be able to wear makeup and go slow dancing...
也不能偷偷溜到停车场去
and run off into the parking lot with that goon.
麦克!
Michael!
停车场？我的女儿？喘气？
Parking lot? My little girl? Heavy breathing?
洛杉矶？
Los Angeles?
别听他的
Don't listen to him, Dad.
父母陪同出席并没有错
You know, chaperoning is not all bad.
什么？
What?
爸爸，我不会干出格的事
Dad, I'm not going to do anything.
很好，有我在
Fine. Then you can not do it with me there.
想打我就打吧
If you want to hit me, I won't stop you.
瞧，我知道不能穿这个
See? I knew it. I can't wear this.
家长应该穿得大方得体，而且要庸俗
Chaperones are supposed to look stodgy and respectable.
那这件怎样？
Well, then why don't you wear this one?
这件衣服庸俗？
You think that dress is stodgy?
这件？
This one?
庸俗？开玩笑的
Stodgy? I'm kidding.
我最喜欢这件了
I love this dress. It's my favorite dress.
做梦都梦见你穿呢
I have dreams about this dress.
好吧
Okay.
我还没来得及告诉你.
Oh, sweetheart, I haven't had the chance to tell you how surprised...
你改变主意 愿、意出席舞会是成熟的表现
and happy I was that you changed your mind and agreed to do this.
我很高兴
It shows real maturity.
我虽然成熟，但童心未泯
Well, that's me. Mature, yet curiously juvenile.
你不是因为凯罗所以去的
And, of course, the fact that Carol's going had nothing to do with it.
凯罗？
Carol who?
不说了
It's okay. It's okay.
你越是保守，我越喜欢
I love you when you're hopelessly old-fashioned.
我们明晚就是要看管好.
You realize this is exactly the sort of behavior we're supposed...
这种行为
to prevent tomorrow night.
但这是今晚
But this is tonight.
生活真奇妙，昨天第一次见面.
Isn't life crazy? I mean, I meet you for the first time yesterday...
后来发现我们都参加了组织委员会
and then I find out that we're on the same decorating committee.
真奇妙
Crazy, crazy, crazy.
我父母今晚要来
My parents are chaperoning tonight.
太遗憾了
I'm sorry.
谢谢你，这消息来得太突然了
Thank you. It came as quite a shock.
可以理解，我父母也试过
I can imagine. My parents chaperoned once.
如何？
How was it?
太可怕了
It was mortifying.
他们
They...
凯罗，他们也跳舞了
Carol, they danced.
天哪!
Oh, my God!
我爸手舞足蹈，像打麦机一样
My father started flailing his arms like some huge thrashing machine.
我妈欢蹦乱跳的.
My mother, she kind of hopped and clapped...
还跟着音乐欢呼
and yelled "Hey" in time to the music.
真是恶梦
What a nightmare.
沃德？
Ward?
阿道夫老师
Mrs. Hinckley.
你又为学校争光了
You've done our school proud, as usual.
谢谢
Thank you, Ward.
若是家长联谊会的女士们都像你.
If all the ladies in the Parents Association were like you...
那我的生活就妙极了
it would sure change my life.
谢谢
Thank you.
你给家长的信，写得很好
We loved your chaperone letter. It really did the trick.
太好了，今晚有家长来了？
Wonderful. Who is chaperoning tonight?
西弗家
The Seavers.
沃德
Ward?
什么事？
Yes?
没什么
I don't know.
也许为人父的在家里执业 做心理治疗是可以的
Maybe it's okay for a man to run a psychiatric practice out of the home...
也许在孩子们最需要时.
and maybe it's all right for a woman to go back to work...
为人母的到外面工作是可以的
just when her children need her most.
也许放纵孩子是可以的
And maybe letting our offspring run wild is hunky-dory.
也许是我太老派
And maybe I'm just old-fashioned.
也许吧
Could be.
沃德.
Ward.
我是怕西弗家.
Ward, I'm worried about the Seavers.
出席舞会的家长.
I mean, the type of people we need for chaperones...
应该是能控制自己子女的家长
should be able to control their own children.
这个要求还真不低
Wow, that's a pretty high standard.
你父母也许更糟糕
Boy, your parents sound worse than mine.
-亲爱的 -你提早回家了
- Hi, honey. - Hi. You're home early.
今天新闻不多
Slow news day.
老爷和太太都回到宫殿了
Oh, well then the lord and lady of the manor...
他们的二人世界
have the castle all to themselves.
大家好
Hey, guys, how you doing?
我去接
I'll get that.
该死的，我不演了
That does it, I quit the play.
你终于不去当那块石头了？
Ben, you're not going to be a rock after all?
不干了
No way.
第二场修道士一直坐在我身上
Friar Tuck sits on me all through Act 2.
好吧，我们下次再当监督人
Well, that's okay then, we can chaperone another time.
谢谢希特勒..阿道夫老师
Well, thank you for calling, Mrs. Hitler... Hinckley.
好，再见
All right. Bye.
-你们不出席了？ -不去了
- You mean we aren't chaperoning? - No.
快掐掐我，不是做梦吧？ 太好了
Somebody pinch me. I'm dreaming. This is great.
不是这样的
No, it's not.
你疯了？
What are you, nuts?
我全知道了
Forget it, I already know the answer.
她告诉你原因了吗？
Did she tell you why?
这个星期的监督人请重复了
Well, apparently they've double-booked the chaperones this week.
她骗你的
Well, she lied to you.
不请你们是因为.
The reason you're not chaperoning is because...
你们是不合格的父母
you're unacceptable parents.
不合格的父母？
Unacceptable parents?
你亲耳听到的？
Carol, you heard this?
不单是我
Not just me.
斯柯蒂每个字都听到了
Scotty Siegler heard every word of it.
好极了!
All right!
我不明白
I don't get it.
她说我妈妈丢下我去工作
She said I have a mother who abandoned me...
哥哥是少年犯，爸爸在家开精神病院
a brother who's a delinquent, a father who runs a mental ward at home.
把我的生活说得像电影一样
She made my life sound like a Movie of the Week.
我宰了她
I'll kill her.
麦姬，别急
Maggie, don't get upset.
杰森，你怎能若无其事的？
Jason, how can you stand there so calmly?
其实我也深深感到愤怒
Actually, I have deeply rooted feelings of anger and hostility.
但是发脾气前我要核实一下 是否存在误解
I just refuse to give vent to them until we find out if there's some misunderstanding.
我可是要发脾气
I'll give her a vent.
明天全校都会传开来了
This will be all over the school by tomorrow.
不会的，别人怎么会听到呢？
Oh, Carol, it will not. How's anybody going to hear?
我没骗你，他们就是这么说的 “不合格”
No, man, I'm not kidding. That's what they said: "unacceptable."
等等，有电话进来了
All right, hold on. I have someone else on the other line.
麦克，这事没什么好炫耀的
Mike, this is nothing to brag about.
我知道，喂？
I know, Dad. Hello?
杰里，你也听到了，对!
Oh, hi, Jerry. Oh, you heard. Yeah!
他们不允许我父母 接近学校1里范围内
They don't want my parents within a mile of that school.
我不要住在这城市了
I'll never live this down.
等等，昨天你们感到丢脸 是因为我们是合格的
Just a minute. Yesterday you were embarrassed because we were acceptable.
正是
Exactly.
现在让我受多大的罪了？
Now do you see what you're putting me through?
真是离谱
This is absolutely unbelievable.
对，我们家是垃圾!
Yeah. We're garbage!
-你答应过不发脾气的 -是的
- Do you promise to hold your temper? - Yes.
-骗我吧？ -是的
- Are you lying? - Yes.
来也，是西弗一家吗？
Hi-ho, you must be the Seavers.
我叫吉姆
Call me Jimbo.
来也
Hi-ho.
进来，今晚有烧烤
Go on in. I have BBQ detail tonight.
瞧？都是有礼貌的人
See? These are reasonable people.
西弗先生，西弗太太
Mr. And Mrs. Seaver, how nice of you...
今日来访真是太客气了
to insist on dropping by.
你好，我叫杰森
Yes, well, hello, my name's Jason.
你好，这到底是.
How do you do? Now what's all this crud about...
阿道夫老师，我们不会打扰你很久
We won't take up much of your time, Mrs. Hinckley.
只是想澄清一点误会
We just thought we should come by and clear up a little misunderstanding.
请坐下
Well, won't you sit down?
好的，谢谢
Yes, yes, we will. Thank you very much.
谣传你说过一些话.
Well, the thing is that we heard this crazy rumor that you said...
也许是搞错了
and this is probably all wrong...
听闻你说我们是不合格的家长
but that you said something about us being "unacceptable" parents.
这话不该传到你们耳朵那里
Oh, dear. I'm afraid that wasn't meant for your ears.
这么说真有其事？
So, you did say that?
是的
Oh, yes.
你干嘛要破坏我们的名誉？
Just where in the hell do you get off ruining our reputation?
我们家很少这样说话
We don't use that word in our home.
-该死的!你.. -“该死”也是
- Damn it! How can you... - Or that one.
我还有三个字要说呢
Well, I have two more words you won't like, June.
什么？
Yes?
没什么，一下子头脑发热了
No, no... Now, I'm getting carried away here.
杰森，没关系，说吧
It's okay, Jason, get carried away.
不，我们是来.
No, no. I would like to make one more attempt...
-但.. -沟通沟通的
- But... ...at some real communication here.
-我.. -斯波特？
- L... - Sport?
晚上出门.
When one goes out for an evening...
穿着要对得上场合
one dresses properly for the occasion.
-可是妈妈你.. -你知道我喜欢什么
- Oh, but, Mother... - You know what Mother likes.
疯婆子!
Nuts!
什么？
Excuse me?
是，妈妈
Yes, Mother.
真是孩子气
Children.
咱们就开门见山吧
Hold on to your slipcovers, June, because I'm gonna...
麦姬，麦姬，这是怎么了？
Maggie, Maggie, Maggie, what's the point?
我们再待下去.
We're not on the same planet here.
这样能解决问题吗？
And if we stay any longer we're just going to make ourselves crazy.
对她骂出脏话来.
And we probably will end up hurling obscenities at this woman...
那又有什么好处呢？
and what would that accomplish?
见鬼!试试看吧
Well, what the heck? Let's give it a shot.
宝贝，汉堡包快好了
June bug, these burgers are very close.
Uh-oh.
嗨，本
Hi, Ben.
嗨
Hi.
哥哥呢？
Where's your brother?
去了舞会
At the dance.
-姐姐呢？ -在房间里
- Where's your sister? - In her room.
沙发呢？
Where's the couch?
不知道，刚才还在
I don't know. It was here a minute ago.
好吧，我来擦干净
Okay, I'll clean it up.
别擦!干脆翘个二郎腿
Don't clean it up! Don't be... Don't worry! Come here. Put those feet up here.
鞋子不用脱，这才像个孩子
Leave those shoes on. Be a kid.
这才是本
This is the way I like Ben.
又脏又懒的真正的孩子
Sloppy, lazy, a real kid.
若我们不是好家长 凯罗成绩会这么好吗？
And if we're such bad parents, how did Carol turn out so well?
对，还有麦克!十全十美
That's right. And Mike! Mike's perfect.
我丧失理智了
Okay, I lost my head.
谁也不能说我们教不好孩子
But the point is, nobody says we did a bad job raising our kids.
谁也不能禁止我们出席舞会
And nobody tells us we can't chaperone.
凯罗，快点，要错过舞会了
Carol? Hurry up! You're late for the dance.
我不去，太丢脸了
I'm not going. I'm too humiliated.
凯罗，没关系，我们也去
Carol, it's all right. We're chaperoning.
太好了，我要扬眉吐气了
Oh, great. My life is an acid bath.
换衣服吧
Let's change.
我去叫人看管本
I'll call the sitter.
爸爸，有好东西让你看
Hey, Dad, you're gonna love this.
也许校规会禁止任何人跟我父母谈话
I wouldn't be surprised if they made it a crime just to talk to my parents.
这衣服可是选对了
Well, I guess you wore the right dress.
坏了
Oh, nuts.
阿道夫!吉姆!
June! Jimbo!
Hey, hey, hey.
挺热闹的
Nice dance.
你们来了也不等于是监督人
The fact that you're here doesn't make you chaperones.
你们来了不等于只有你们来了
And the fact that you're here doesn't mean you're here.
下面我们要对长辈们致敬
Okay, now let's go way back and do a little tribute to our ancestors.
这是老摇滚音乐
Here's some genuine fogy rock...
监督人也要跳
and that means our chaperones must dance.
监督人是你们吧？
Well, as you pointed out, you're the chaperones.
麦姬，怎么看？
Well, Maggie, what do you say?
我说.
I say...
我永远也不能回到这个学校了
I'll never be able to come back to this school again.
不，这种污点过一两年就会淡去
No, don't worry. The stigma fades after a year or two.
其实你爸妈跳得不错
You know, actually, your parents aren't too bad. Look.
跳舞的是你父母吗？
Hey, are those your parents dancing?
不，我父母今晚没空
No, no. My parents couldn't make it tonight.
他们好像出国去了
They may have to leave the country.
是他们
Oh, no, that's them.
-谁？ -瞧他们跳得多棒
- Who? - The ones with all the moves.
你知道是谁教他们跳的吗？
Hey, hey, come on, who do you think showed them all those moves?
你父母还真酷呢
You know, your parents are reasonably cool.
当然，还用说
Sure, what'd you expect?
为第一名欢呼!
Let's hear it for couple number one!
为第二名欢呼!
And couple number two!
爸妈，这是斯柯蒂
Mom, Dad, this is Scotty Siegler.
-嗨 -嗨
- Hi. - Hi.
-他送我回家可以吗？ -可以
- Is it okay if he walks me home? - Sure.
爸爸你!
But, Dad!
Oh.
谢谢!
Okay. Thanks!
好吧.
Okay. All right...
今晚你们可以自由一点 但别得意忘形
you guys got away with it once. I don't want this to go to your heads.
妈，这套衣服也太火辣了
This is a hot dress, Mom.
以后别在我朋友面前穿了
And please, don't ever wear it in front of my friends again.
麦克，回家去
Mike, go home.
我玩得很开心
Well, I had fun.
我也是
So did I.
真的是老摇滚
Fogy rock, indeed.
好吧，老家伙
Well, let's go, fogy.
摇滚吧
Let's rock.
[zeroxia@gmail.com] 2006.04.01